businesstraveller.com 2018-12-31

# Privacy Policy – Business Traveller

Panacea Media Limited, its subsidiaries and associates (‘Panacea’) collect information from our Users whether you browse as a guest or during the registration process.  We try and make the process as rapid and straightforward as possible and we are grateful for the information our Users provide.

As examples information is gathered for website functionality; to provide improved or personalised services to you; to help decide what kind of advertising you will see on the site; and, in accordance with your chosen preferences, to market goods or services to you.

The more accurate the information we receive from each User, the more specific we can be in our ongoing contact with them. This Privacy Policy sets out our information-gathering and dissemination practices for this Site (businesstraveller.com). Please also see our website terms and conditions.

We are not responsible for the content or privacy practices of external sites, third party Apps or your chosen internet browser. However, we do seek to explain how we work with third parties, including search engines and ad servers such as Google. You can see Google’s Privacy Policy [here](https://policies.google.com/technologies/partner-sites).

This Privacy and Cookie Policy explains how we use any of your personal information we might collect and how you can limit our use of it.

**Overview**

Panacea and this Site will comply with all relevant English Data Protection laws, so any personal details to be provided to us will not be disclosed to third parties outside Panacea without the User’s consent.

Users should be aware and accept that, if Panacea is requested by authorised third parties or regulatory or governmental agencies investigating illegal activities to provide information concerning Users activities whilst using the Site, the business shall do so.

Similarly, Panacea will disclose Users’ personal data if Panacea is compelled to do so by law. Panacea reserves the right to notify or provide such information to the relevant authority if, in our sole opinion, Panacea believe an emergency, illegal activity or some other reasonable basis exists for us doing so.

  1. **_What information do we gather?_**

The information that we gather falls broadly into two types (please see further below for how we collect it and what we use it for):

1.1 Information that relates directly to you (e.g. your name and contact details, communication preferences and customer history).

1.2 Information that does not directly identify you (e.g. how you might browse our website), specifically:

(1) Your IP address through the placement of cookies; and

(2) Location data, which might be gained through your IP address or GPS data (see Section 3 (3), below).

Please note that not all cookies are either personally identifiable information or even unique identifiers; but some can be, while others can influence what you see on our website and others (see Sections 6 and 7 on cookies and their management, below).

  2. **_How we use your information_**

2.1 When we seek your permission. Often, we will be using your information in accordance with your specific consent or instructions: for example, because you have requested or consented to receiving certain information or entered into a contract with us for goods and services: see Section 2.2 below.

At other times we will use your information on one of the other lawful bases described below in this section.

2.2 Contract.

(1) When you enter into a contract for goods or services with us (including competitions, offers, subscriptions or your online Business Traveller account), or where you wish to register an interest in doing so, we will use your personal data to enter into and fulfil our contractual relationship with you.

(2) Fulfilling our contract with you means being able to manage and administer our services, and maintain our standards of tailored service levels, customer care and consumer compliance. This might include fulfilling orders or returns, processing payments or refunds, and providing aftercare, as well as improving your customer experience online and otherwise, including by monitoring service levels and responding to feedback.

2.3 Legitimate interests.

Other uses of your information are made for ordinary and transparent purposes which we think are necessary for our legitimate interests as a provider of news, content, and other services. We use your information on this basis to do the following:

(1) Recognise and remember you when you visit our website and better understand how you use our website and others by using cookies to follow your use. We explain what cookies are in Section 6 and how you can manage them in Section 7, below;

(2) Serve you advertisements on selected, third-party websites that make their advertising space available to us.  We call this “Audience Extension” and we do this by using retargeting cookies. We explain what cookies are in Section 6 and how you can manage them in Section 7, below;

(3) Identify your interests. We might then put your information in aggregated form into groupings (known as “segments”) by a particular audience, which means we can serve you advertisements and offers that will interest you within the website, including by reference to data we receive from third parties. Please see Sections 6 and 7 for more information about cookies and how we serve you more targeted messaging;

(4) Keep you updated on any services you have subscribed to, or any products you have purchased, and/or about similar services unless you have told us otherwise (including where we are working alongside other Service Providers to provide these services, such as travel or insurance);

(5) Contact you to let you know about any of our products, services or promotions (which may in some cases be provided by third parties), including by email and always having regard to your preferences. Please see Section 4 to understand more about how you provide and can manage your preferences.

(6) Make sure materials on the website or in apps are presented in the most effective way for you and your computer or mobile device;

(7) Collect and log numeric internet addresses to improve the website and to monitor website usage; and

(8) Assess and understand our readers’, customers, site users’ and account holders’ feedback and identify usage hotspots;

2.4 Some limited uses of your data are required to comply with legal obligations, for example fraud detection and taxation;

  3. **_How do we gather information?_**

3.1 Information (as set out in Section 1) is gathered in the following ways:

(1) indirectly (e.g. using website technology that tracks and administers your visits through your browser, or when you log on and/or share stories through social media;

(2) directly (e.g. when you buy a subscription, sign up to create a businesstraveller.com profile, or you otherwise provide your information when you interact with us);

(3) through your device (e.g. mobile, PC or tablet) where you have enabled location services for the applicable App or browser. This is used to show you editorial content relevant to your location and may be used for location targeted services or advertising in accordance with your preferences, which may be adjusted either on your device or via server, App or website preferences;

(4) when you subscribe to Business Traveller, we may also use a card updater service to automatically update your credit or debit card details. This service is facilitated by your credit or debit card issuer, whom you should contact for further information;

(5) we may also overlay additional demographic and lifestyle data from Choozle (www.Choozle.com) to help us understand what else you might be interested in for direct marketing and insight purposes. These segmentations are built using a variety of sources, including publicly available data (such as the electoral register and the UK Census) or derived from surveys and questionnaires. You can opt out of having your personal information profiled in this way by contacting us. See Section 5, below.

  4. **_How do you decide how you want to hear from us?_**

4.1 We will contact you in accordance with your preferences, including by email, phone and post.  We always seek to explain why and how we might contact you at the point you give your information to us.

4.2 We also provide the means for you to grant or withhold your permission for us to contact you. We do this by using opt-in boxes or unsubscribe options, which determine your permission for us to contact you.

4.3 Sometimes, we need your information to be able to contact you to provide the service you wish to use (e.g. a subscription or Business Traveller Offers). In those cases, by signing up to the service you are agreeing that we will have to send you service communications to run the service itself, and we will not offer you the chance to opt-out from receiving those messages until you decide you no longer wish to use the services.

4.4 As well as the communications we send you, we also offer you the opportunity to choose whether to hear from specific companies and organisations that we work in association with. We will always name those companies and organisations, and you will have to opt in to hearing from them via a tick box (or because you choose to engage with them directly).

  5. **_Accessing and updating your personal information_**

5.1 You can update or delete your details and marketing preferences by emailing our subscription department, by emailing [subscriptions@businesstraveller.com](mailto:subscriptions@businesstraveller.com)  or accessing your account pages on the website or by writing to us at Business Traveller, 41-43 Maddox Street, London, W1S 2PD.

5.2 You have the right to access the personal information held about you from us, or from any other organisation that controls your personal information. To understand how to obtain a copy of the personal information that we hold, please see Section 13 [link].

  6. **_Cookies_**

6.1 A cookie is a small piece of information that is placed on your computer when you visit certain websites. When we refer to “cookies” we include other technologies with similar purposes, such as tags and identifiers. Find out more about the use of cookies on <http://www.cookiecentral.com/>.

6.2 When you first visit our sites using a new browser, or if you visit in private browsing mode, we will provide you with a cookies permission banner seeking your consent to use of cookies as required by law. From this banner you will be able to access our cookies management tool. By clicking OK or clicking through to any part of the site, we will start to manage your visit using cookies.

6.3 We use the following types of cookie, as will your browser:

(1) Analytics cookies that anonymously remember your computer or mobile device when you visit our website. They keep track of browsing patterns and help us to build up a profile of how our readers use the website. We use that information for customer analytics and to serve advertisements that we think might be of particular interest to you on our and other websites. Your browser may use similar cookies for similar purposes and to serve advertisements for others.

(2) Service cookies that help us to make our website work as efficiently as possible; remember your registration and login details; remember your settings preferences; to detect what device you are using and adapt how we present our services according to the screen size of that device.

(3) Third party advertising and analytics cookies, which are placed by or on behalf of independent advertisers who are advertising on our site. These cookies may be placed within the advertisement and elsewhere on our site by us or by your browser. They are anonymous – they cannot be used to identify individuals, but they can also allow the advertiser or your browser to tailor advertising to you when you visit other websites using the same browser. They are used for statistical analysis by allowing the advertiser to count how many people have seen their advertisement or have seen it more than once, to make sure you are not repeatedly served with the same advertising messages.

6.3 We have no access to third party cookies and third party organisations have no access to ours. The third party organisations that place cookies, including your browser (such as Google) and the third party companies who pay for advertising and analytics services using this information, will have their own privacy policies.

  7. **_Managing your cookies preferences_**

7.1 Most browsers allow you to turn off cookies. To do this look at the “help” menu on your browser. Switching off cookies may restrict your use of the website and/or delay or affect the way in which it operates. We also provide our own cookie management tool for you to make more specific choices about how cookies are used for your visits to our site.

7.2 We also use third party cookies, as will your browser. These are cookies that may be read by third parties (for example if you have used social sign-on and have the option to like or comment using your social media account).

Alternatively, visit [www.youronlinechoices.com](http://www.youronlinechoices.com/) or click on the AdChoices logo that you will see in the corner of advertisements that carry behavioural targeting cookies.

7.3 We use various third parties to provide us with information to help us learn about how users use our website. To find out more about how we use these third party services click on their names, below, to view their websites and privacy policies:

7.4 If you would like to disable “third party” cookies generated by advertisers or providers of targeted advertising services, you can turn them off by going to the third party’s website and getting them to generate a one-time “no thanks” cookie that will stop any further cookies being written to your device. Here is a link to the third party advertising platform we use, which has instructions on how to do this:

<https://adssettings.google.com/authenticated>

Please note that even after disabling this, you may still see “non-personalised” advertisements that may appear materially the same as the “personalised” ones. This is simply a function of what advertisers and partners we are working with, and does not mean your preferences have not been applied.

Please note also that the likes of Google, with whom we work to serve advertising, will still use cookies for necessary administrative purposes after you have amended your personalised advertising settings. These purposes include frequency capping (namely to stop users being served the same advertisements repeated), aggregated reporting of engagement (on a non-personal basis) and to combat fraud and abuse (for example, to prevent bogus click-throughs by web hosts to inflate the value of their platform).

7.5 We also use a data management platform. We use the data this platform records to better understand our users’ interests, so that we can provide better and relevant Panacea and Advertiser services based on this information.

7.6 When you share stories using social media, for example Facebook, the social media company will drop cookies and identifiers to track this.

7.7 You can also visit the trade body representing these advertising companies for more information on how to opt out of these cookies: <http://youronlinechoices.com/>

  8. **_Ad Blockers_**

8.1 We may display a message to advise you that we have detected that you are using and ad blocker

8.2 As advertising is key to funding Businesstraveller.com we reserve the right to restrict your access to some or all of our website while you have an ad blocker turned on.

  9. **_Protecting your information_**

9.1 The password you provide when registering with the website is encrypted to ensure protection against unauthorised access to your personal information.

9.2 We invest in high-quality security and do our utmost to protect user privacy. No data transmission over the Internet can be entirely secure, and therefore we cannot guarantee the security of your personal information and/or use of the website. Any information that you send is at your own risk and may be read by others. However once we have received your personal information we use strict procedures to protect the security of your personal information.

  10. **_Disclosing your information_**

10.1 Selling our businesses. We may disclose your personal information to third parties and their advisers if we are approached by a potential buyer in connection with the potential sale of our business or of any part of it.  Should we proceed to sell or reconstitute any part of our business that holds your personal information, it will be necessary in some circumstances to share or transfer that information to the buyer or new entity: for example, so that they can continue to provide continuity of service to you. You will always be notified of such a change of control or ownership, and will be given the opportunity to object or opt out of any further communications from us or the buyer or new entity, except where such use of your personal information is necessary for a lawful purpose (such as a legal obligation or right, or where necessary to perform an existing contract with you)

10.2 Your internet browser or other accounts.

Depending on which browser you use to visit our site, and in accordance with your browser cookie preferences (see above), your browser (such as Google) may collect information about you and your visit for its own services, including those services such as segmented or personalised advertising that it provides to us and other sites.

10.3 Our partners.  Except as set out in Section 10.1 or 10.2 above, we never sell personal information, or pass it to third parties outside of Panacea, without your permission. We sometimes provide your personal information to third parties who are our subcontractors or providers of various products and services on our behalf e.g. mailing houses in order to fulfil your print subscription. Your personal information will always be subject to appropriate protections under contract. Where you are engaging with Panacea for products and services, you will sometimes contract with our Service Providers and may choose to provide them with personal information or permissions directly.

10.4 Legal requirements. We may disclose your personal information if we are required to do so by law, or if in good faith we believe such action is necessary to comply with the law a legal obligation.

10.5 Verification of circulation figures. We may disclose subscribers’ personal information including: name, address, email address and telephone number and payment details (though no bank or credit card account details) to the Audit Bureau of Circulation (ABC) for the sole purpose of verifying our magazine and website circulation figures.  ABC’s Privacy Policy can be found [here](https://www.abc.org.uk/privacy-policy).

10.6 Data processors. In common with most organisations, some of our functions using your personal information are outsourced to contractors (for example, magazine distributors). Any processing of personal information by these contractors will only be for these carefully defined purposes, and will be adequately and lawfully protected under contract, including requirements of confidentiality and data security.

  11. **_Where we store your personal information_**

11.1 The personal information that we collect from you may sometimes be sent and stored outside the European Economic Area (“EEA”) in order to carry out the activities listed in “Use of Your Information”. Except where this is on your specific instructions, this will always be subject to adequate safeguards as to the protection and security of your personal data. Further details are available on enquiry from [enquiries@panaceapublishing.com](mailto:enquiries@panaceapublishing.com).

11.2 We will only keep your personal information for as long as we need it for a lawful purpose: whether because of the products and services we have provided to you, for example as a subscriber or registered user (and to allow for reasonable retention of records afterwards to reflect legal requirements or limitation periods), or because we believe you still wish to hear from us. This is again separate from our role as a media organisation and the information we are lawfully able keep in the public interest because it is relevant to our journalism and publishing activities.

  12. **_Changes to this Policy_**

12.1 If we change our Policy, we will post the changes on this page. Please check the website regularly for any changes to this Policy. However, from 25 May 2018 any significant changes will be provided to you directly where possible.

  13. **_If you don’t feel we’re adhering to this Policy, what should you do?_**

13.1        You have the following rights:

(1)  To obtain access to, and copies of, the personal data that we hold about you, or require that it is transmitted to another data controller;

(2)  To request that we restrict our data processing activities or cease processing your personal data in certain ways, for example because you do not consider it lawful;

(3)  To require us not to send you marketing communications;

(4)  To withdraw your consent, where we are relying on it to process your personal data;

(5)  To object to how we process your personal data, in particular where we are relying on our legitimate interests; and

(6)  To ask us to erase the personal data we hold about you, for example because it is causing you distress or you believe it to be no longer relevant, or to correct the information if it is incorrect.

Please note that the above rights are not absolute, and we will be entitled to refuse requests where exceptions apply.  You can find out more about your rights at [www.ico.org.uk](https://ico.org.uk/for-organisations/guide-to-the-general-data-protection-regulation-gdpr/individual-rights/)

  14. **_Automated decision making_**

You also have the right to object to automated decision-making, including by means of profiling. Although we use various algorithms and automated criteria to help us serve advertising in the manner set out in this Policy, this results in segmented advertising (by category of user) rather than specific decisions being made about you. This can in any event be controlled through your cookie and ad preferences.

If we change how we use this technology in the future, we will let you know if it affects you via this Policy (and significant changes or effects we will notify directly).

14.1 If you believe that we have not adhered to this Policy, please notify us by email at [enquiries@panaceapublishing.com](mailto:enquiries@panaceapublishing.com) and we will try to solve the problem promptly. If you are not satisfied with our response, or have any other queries, you can also contact the Information Commissioner at [http://www.ico.org.uk](http://www.ico.org.uk/) or 0303 123 1113.
